LAXMAN PARAB

laxmanparab7@gmail.com

+91 96193 51438

laxmanparab.codes



linkedin.com/in/laxmanparab25

Mumbai, Maharashtra

github.com/Laxman-Parab

Summary

Analytics professional organized with interpersonal, productive and communication skills. Individual with the passion to extract meaningful insights using Python, SQL, PowerBi, Excel and SPSS. A proactive and fast learning individual currently working as a Data Scientist at Jio Platforms Limited, utilizing logical & analytical skills in a proficient way to help the corporate achieve business goals.

Skills



Languages Python, SQL and DAX.

Database Microsoft SQL Server and MySQL Workbench.

Data Validation, VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables and Charts. **Excel Analytics**

Business Intelligence Microsoft Power BI and Tableau.

Other Skills IBM SPSS, Statistical Data Analysis, Machine Learning,

Presentation Skills, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Research.

Experience



Analyst Data Science / Deputy Manager

Oct 2022- Present

Jio Platforms Limited



Data Science and Business Analytics Intern.

Aug 2021- Sep 2021

The Sparks Foundation

Education



SOMAIYA VIDYAVIHAR UNIVERSITY, MUMBAI

2020 - 2022

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Statistics **CGPI 9.55**



BHAVAN'S COLLEGE, MUMBAI

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Statistics **CGPI 8.10**

Projects

Stock Tracker Using Microsoft Excel

- Tracking NASDAQ and NSE stocks using the stock widget.
- Calculated personal investment information using excel aggregation function.
- Basic formatting based on profit/loss and determining whether to hold or sell a stock using 'IF' function.

Sales Analysis Using Python

- Focused on performing Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA).
- Discovered the best month for sales, most sold products and city with maximum orders using data visualization.
- Visualized products frequently purchased together using bar plot and pie chart.

Covid Analysis Using SQL

- Calculated total cases by population and total deaths country wise using 'WHERE' and 'ORDER BY' clauses.
- Discovered top 10 countries and top 3 continents with highest death rate using 'TOP' and 'GROUP BY' clauses.
- Used Common Table Expression (CTE) to perform calculation, created a temp table and View to store the data.

Covid Vaccination Analysis Using Microsoft PowerBi

- Created a date table and performed calculations using Data Analysis Expressions (DAX).
- Visualized the data by creating a dashboard.

Certifications

- 1. Data Science Specialization Internshala
- Data Analysis Using Python IBM
- 3. The SQL Micro Degree Udemy
- 4. Microsoft Excel from A-Z Udemy